Phillip Webb

iamphillipwebb
 phillip.webb@nntp.uk
 07719 123327

ABOUT

A developer with strong foundation in HTML, PHP and MySQL. Currently exploring Vue.JS, Cloudflare Workers KV and D1. I am interested in learning new languages and technologies for personal and professional projects, with previous experience using Golang, Java and Google Apps Script.

EMPLOYMENT

Development Engineer

Ennov, St. Neots

November, 2021 – Present

Part of a Scrum team developing a pharmacovigilance web application (Angular, Java, Oracle); building search and administrative features for user access, reporting and product management.

- Implementing security enhancements to prevent unauthorised API data access
- Optimising data export capabilities with Apache POI for efficient data handling
- · Architecting Spring Boot microservices with scalable API endpoints
- Managing Jenkins deployment pipelines and conducting peer code reviews
- Implementing Jasmine unit tests to ensure JavaScript application reliability

Angular, Bash Scripting, CSS, DevExtreme, Git, Golang, HTML, IntelliJ IDEA, Jasmine, Java, JavaScript, Jenkins, Linux, Liquibase, Microservices, Oracle, REST APIs, Redmine, SQL, Scrum, Solr, Spring Data JPA, TypeScript

Software Support Analyst

Ennov, St. Neots

November, 2013 – November, 2021

Experienced in managing and supporting a pharmacovigilance database, troubleshooting software issues, providing user support, and ensuring data integrity.

- Delivered technical support and user training, efficiently resolving support tickets
- Implemented system and database enhancements to improve functionality and performance
- Generated monthly issue reports for custom insights and tracking
- Developed C# .NET utilities to streamline internal support team workflows
- Created a web-based troubleshooting interface for customer connectivity diagnostics

Autolt3, Batch Scripting, Google Apps Script, Liquibase, Oracle, PV-Works, RemoteApp, SQL, Webhooks, XML, XSLT

Helpdesk Analyst

Tensor, St. Neots

July, 2010 – October, 2013

Application and hardware support for customers using Tensor time and attendance, access control, personnel and energy management systems. Security vetted as non-police personnel by West Midlands Police.

- Microsoft SQL and MSDE database configuration and support
- Technical hardware installation guidance given to electrical engineers
- Firmware and software upgrades executed using remote access tools
- Application server migration and software installation support

Service Desk Analyst NHS Anglia Support Partnership, Huntingdon **†** February, 2010 – July, 2010 First line service desk role delivering IT and Facilities support to NHS Strategic Health Authority and Primary Care Trust staff across the Anglia region. • Microsoft Windows Active Directory account administration • Microsoft Exchange 2007 account management via OWA • Enforcing NHS Trust IT and email policies Microsoft Office 2003/2007 application support Hornbill Service Desk, Microsoft Active Directory, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Outlook Software Support Analyst Itim, Huntingdon December, 2006 – February, 2010 Second line support role, including out-of-hours support for retailers in the UK and Europe using Itim end-to-end retail applications. EFT and EPoS software and hardware support for shop floor and back office teams • Responsible for EPoS provision and management for new and refitted stores Resolved support requests using remote access applications Microsoft SQL and DP4 database management DP4, EFT, EPOS, Microsoft SQL, Remote Access, VNC, YesPay Support Technician iCare UK, St. Neots May, 2005 – November, 2006 IT support role for UK and European customers in small or home office environments. In addition to this role I provided administrative support to Sales staff. • Provided Microsoft Windows and Office application support to customers Maintained records of customer requests, incidents and assets • Produced quotes, invoices and contracts for scheduled work • Gave technical sales advice to customers MacOS X, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Windows Baker ☐ June, 2004 – November, 2006 Hotspot Bakery, St. Neots A skilled baker with experience producing frozen pies, pastries, bread and cakes while maintaining high standards of quality and safety. · Operated bakery equipment and maintained a clean workspace to comply with regulations Managed inventory of ingredients and supplies to meet production demands • Ensured quality and standards to maintain product consistency

- Contributed with team members to increase efficiency of the production process

Hardware Technician

 T-Auctions **July**, 2003 – June, 2004

IT recycling technician with hands-on experience in managing the lifecycle of decommissioned electronic equipment.

- Efficiently processed pallets of printers, monitors, desktop and notebook computers
- Destroyed data to ensure compliance with data protection regulations
- Cleaned and refurbished devices to meet quality standards for resale
- Imaged devices in preparation for onsite, and online auction sales

EDUCATION

盦	The Open University		
9	Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire		🛱 February, 2014 – Present
	 Web Technologies (TT284) Discovering Mathematics (MU123) Technologies in Practice (TM129) My Digital Life (TU100) 		
盒	Peterborough Regional College		
9	Peterborough, Cambridgeshire	:	September, 1999 – January, 2003
	 Information & Communication Technology, GNVQ Intermediate Sports, Recreation and Allied Occupations Leadership, NVQ Level 2 Adult Numeracy, NVQ Level 1 		
盦	Ernulf Community School		
Q	St. Neots, Cambridgeshire	:	September, 1993 – January, 1998
	• English, GCSE		

☆ INTERESTS

Humanities, GCSEMathematics, GCSE

• Theatre Studies, GCSE

Music, GCSEScience, GCSE

I regularly play inline hockey with St. Neots Sharks. As a member of the club committee I am responsible for provision of email and web hosting services. Skaters confirm attendance for each session using an online register, which I developed and maintain using PHP, Vue.JS and SQLite/MariaDB

I am passionate about information technology, with emphasis on on cybersecurity and open-source operating systems. As a Linux enthusiast, I actively maintain a home lab comprising several self-hosted services, which help me develop my computing knowledge.